Guide to the Records of the Office of Development, NYU Libraries RG.38.28
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of Development, NYU Libraries
1983-2015
New York University Archives
New York University. Library. Office of Development
RG.38.28
1.25 linear feet in 1 record carton and 1 half manuscript box
The Office of Development, NYU Libraries, fosters public engagement with the Libraries through events such as lectures and exhibitions, and through the Progressions newsletter and other donor-directed publications. The department also raises money for Libraries projects and programs through proposals to foundations and individuals, and through the Friends of Bobst Library program. This collection consists of materials created and collected by the Office of Development during the 1980s through early 2000s. Materials in this collection include event invitations, photographic prints and contact sheets, publications produced and distributed by both the Library and the wider University, and memoranda and correspondence documenting the administrative efforts related to planning various Library lectures, award celebrations, and other events.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by the NYU Libraries Office of Development during the 1980s through early 2000s. Materials in this collection include event invitations, photographic prints and contact sheets, publications produced and distributed by both the Library and the wider University, and memoranda and correspondence documenting the administrative efforts related to planning various Library lectures, award celebrations, and other events.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Historical Note
The Office of Development, NYU Libraries, fosters public engagement with the Libraries through events such as lectures and exhibitions, and through the Progressions newsletter and other donor-directed publications. The department also raises money for Libraries projects and programs through proposals to foundations and individuals, and through the Friends of Bobst Library program.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to the New York University Archives by the Office of Development, NYU Libraries, in August and September 2017; the accession numbers associated with these transfers are 2017.031 and 2018.001.
Private universities and colleges -- Administration -- United States.; Education, Higher -- United States.; Education, Higher -- Awards; Academic libraries -- New York (N.Y.); Fales Library
- Barbara Goldsmith Dinner, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Barbara Goldsmith Lecture, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Barbara Goldsmith Lecture, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Barbara Goldsmith Event, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Billion Dollar Gala, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bobst Library 10th Anniversary, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bobst Library 20th Anniversary -- General, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bobst Library 20th Anniversary -- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bobst Library 20th Anniversary -- Memoranda, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bobst Library 20th Anniversary -- Plaques, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Bobst Library 30th Anniversary, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
- Bobst Library Awards, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- Bobst Library Awards -- Carlton Rochell Remarks, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Bobst Literary Awards, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Brawer Lecture, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Brochures, 2002-2011 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Cohen Lecture, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Dinner Honoring King Hussein I of Jordan -- Draft Remarks, 1996-05-31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Elmer Holmes Bobst Award in Arts and Letters for Emerging Writers, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fales Dinner Contact Sheets, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Fales Lecture, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Irwin Mann Memorial Lecture, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Leonard Silk and Uner Kirdar Reception, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- NYU Alumni, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- NYU Leadership Conference, John Sexton Address, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- NYU Press Prizes for Fiction and Poetry, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Photography, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Publications and Ephemera, 1994-2015 (Box 1, Folder 30-33, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Vardis J. Vardinoyannis Library of Hellenic Civilization Dedication, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)